Kota Kawaguchi

Application Developer

•

81-904-716-1544

kota.k.1132.pda@gmail.com

0

Kawasaki, Kanagawa, Japan 2130013

CAREER OBJECTIVE

I am Software Developer with 2.5 year's experience in E-Commerce industry.

I am mainly involved in the back-end development of item's inventory management and order transfer, but also in the front-end and infrastructure areas. I am also well versed in operational tasks such as load testing in preparation for a sale. In graduate school, I was engaged in research on data mining using natural language processing. I was selected as a JASSO scholarship recipient for exemption from repayment for my achievements during my studies, including external presentations at peer-reviewed international conferences. Currently, I would like to get an opportunity to work as a backend engineer to work on new product development.

EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER (FULL-TIME, FREELANCE), Minato, Tokyo

Enigmo, February 2022-Present

- Developed workflows to transfer items and order data with overseas boutique's API with Apache Airflow.
- Created BI dashboard to monitor data transfer status with BigQuery and Looker
- Set up infra services on GCP with Terraform.
- Upgraded Airflow and Cloud Composer Version from 1.0 to 2(Airflow 2.2.3, Cloud Composer 2.0.9)
- Migrated GCP project and existing data to scale the application system.

APPLICATION ENGINEER, Setagaya, Tokyo

Rakuten Group, April 2020-February 2022

- Implemented the product spec data transfer batch system.

 Designed and implemented abstract and concrete class
- Developed API and frontend application of internal management system.
- Created CI/CD pipeline with Jenkins and wrote IaC with Chef and yaml files for k8s to deploy applications.
- Executed stress test and tuned Nginx settings to increase system performance.
- Designed system architecture and developed load balancing function for time sale items.

RESEARCH INTERN, Chiyoda, Tokyo

Z Holdings Corporation, July 2018-June 2019

- Generated machine learning models to estimate user attributes using text data from Twitter
- Analyzed user behavior and user interests using news site app users' browsing log data
- Implemented a categorization model using disaster-related text data from Twitter

EDUCATION

MASTER OF ENGINEERING IN INTELLIGENT AND MECHANICAL INTERACTION SYSTEMS, Tsukuba, IBARAKI

University Of Tsukuba, March 2020

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING IN MECHANICAL ENGINEERING, Tsukuba, IBARAKI

University Of Tsukuba, March 2018

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

Python (3.5y): Developed DAG With Airflow, And Used For Research In Natural Language Processing

Java (Spring Boot)(2y): Used In The Backend Of A Home Appliances EC Site And In The Backend Of An In-House Tool

JavaScript, TypeScript (Vue.Js, Angular)(2y): Used In Front-End Of A Home Appliances EC Site

Kubernetes(2.5y): Each Web Application And API Are Operated On Kubernetes.

GCP(6m): Developed Cloud Composer, And Used BigQuery, Cloud Build, Cloud VPN, GCS, Looker, IAM Management

Terraform(2.5y): Set Up GCP Components With Terraform.

Nginx(2y): Used As Reverse Proxy Of EC Site, And Did Parameter Tuning

Google App Script (3m): Transfer Order Data With External API

CERTIFICATIONS

Google Cloud Certified Associate Cloud Engineer

AWARDS

 Repayment Exemption for Students with Excellent Grades Issued by Japan Student Services Organization (JASSO) · Jul 2020

PUBLICATIONS

 BERT based Web Mining of Concerns and Reviews for TV Drama AudienceBERT based Web Mining of Concerns and Reviews for TV Drama Audience Proceeding WI '19 Companion IEEE/WIC/ACM International Conference on Web Intelligence - Volume 24800 Pages 64-71